DAVID EISENMENGER

UX DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

A user experience designer and researcher with a diverse background in healthcare, social work, and nonprofit managment. My focus is to help create seamless user experiences that work well, make people happy, and add value to the product. I have an extensive history focused on wellbeing in the user's experience.

CONTACT

101 Stevenson Ave Louisville, KY 40206

502.468.4978 david@heronblue.design www.heronblue.design

SKILLS

Research

Interview

Survey

Comparative Analysis

Usability Testing

Design

Persona

Journey Mapping
Wireframing

Prototyping

Tools

Sketch

Adobe Creative Suite

InVision

Languages

HTML/CSS JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

David Eisenmenger DBA HeronBlue Design

Dec 2017 - Present

Freelance Designer

Front end web development and user experience design for clients. Recent projects include human centered design, iterative testing, and design for mobile, user research.

Friendship Health and Rehab

Feb 2016 - Present

Director of Social Services

Focus on customer experience and patient wellbeing. CMS health inspection star rating increased from one to three stars Feb 2016 to present.

Signature Healthcare, LLC

May 2013 - Feb 2016

Director of Education Research and Programming

Designed, developed, and deployed training for 113 healthcare facilities. Programs include: wellbeing at end of life, workplace diversity and inclusion, emotional intelligence, Post test showed avg 15% increase in emotional intelligence in participants.

Signature Healthcare, LLC

Oct 2009 - May 2013

Director of Spirituality

Led initiatives focused on patient and staff wellbeing. In a high tunover field, average monthly nursing turnover reduced by a 3% in 12 month period. Community Outreach Award for program adding value to the patient, family, community connection. CMS deficiency free annual surveys 2012, 2013.

EDUCATION

User Experience Design Course

May 2018 - March 2019

Springboard

Front End Web Development Track

Sept 2017 - Mar 2018

Code Louisville

M.A. Marriage and Family Therapy Louisville Presbyterian Theological Seminary Aug 2005 - May 2007

B.A. Peace and Global Studies

Aug 1999 - May 2001

Earlham College